Samuel Brandão

Software Engineer

contact

Via Padova, 178 Milan, 20132 - Italy +39 3894570300

gb.samuel@gmail.com linkedin.com/in/sambrandao github.com/khamusa bitbucket.org/khamusa

languages

portuguese native english fluency italian fluency

techs

Puby (& Rails)
Python 3
PostgreSQL, MySQL
MongoDB
Git
JavaScript
Angular, JQuery
CSS3 & HTML5
Heroku
AWS
Elastic Search
RabbitMQ
F#

concepts

Erlang

♥ Software Design
♥ Agile development
♥ Functional Programming
♥ BDD Workflows
Database Design
Performance Optimization
MetaProgramming

summary

Accomplished software engineer with 8+ years of experience building products (SaaS) using a range of technologies including Ruby/Rails, Python and JavaScript with multiple frameworks, relational and NoSQL databases.

experience

apr/2016-now

Lead Developer at Lets.events

Development & Technical Leadership

- ♦ Key participation in project management and technical decision making processes.
- ◆ Scrum Master / Implementation of Scrum methodology for the webapp development team.
- ◆ Full Stack Developer.

apr/2015-2016 Senior Developer at 77Agency/Allin1Social

http://www.allin1social.com, Italy

https://lets.events

- ♦ Performed extensive bugfixing, reduced the legacy code complexity, improved code design and quality according to every measurable metric.
- ♦ Reduced the time spent by support staff by creating tools that brought to surface the most critical issues affecting the clients experience.
- ♦ Improved the data retrieval, integration and processing mechanism, both by optimizing existing tasks and also by applying advanced heuristics, which led to an 82% reduction of the overall daily/hourly workload, and a considerable service reliability boost.
- ◆ Main technologies used: Ruby / Rails, MongoDB, Redis, JS / ReactJS.

2004-apr/2015

Freelance Developer

Brazil, Italy

Developer

Worked as a Freelance Developer since 2004, having worked with a coprehensive set of technologies, including Ruby, Python, PHP (using Codelgniter, Wordpress, Magento), JS/CoffeeScript, AngularJs and ReactJs.

particular projects

2012-2014 Miviro / Lead Developer

http://www.miviro.com.br

A social network/management tool for tour agencies

2011 Wertix CMS

Own project

Visual Content Management System

education

2011-2015

Bachelor of Computer Science, graduated *cum laude* Laurea in Informatica

Università degli Studi di Milano

about me

I started programming at the age of 11 and working professionaly at the age of 19. While being a self-taught programmer contributed significantly to my problem solving skills, completing my Bachelors Degree in Milan granted me a more comprehensive view of the whole technological ecosystem. I worked on different types of projects and teams, and have been focusing on SAAS products for the last few years. I am naturally passionate about software development and I pursue pragmatism on my work on a daily basis. I've also worked as a professional theater actor in Brazil. I am a fan of cats, daily exercises and midfulness meditation.